<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-23T21:00:09+00:00</updated><id>http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">The Lab Receives a Plasticity of Well-Being Network Secondary Data Analysis Grant</title><link href="http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/2025/04/01/PWB-grant.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Lab Receives a Plasticity of Well-Being Network Secondary Data Analysis Grant" /><published>2025-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-23T20:57:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/2025/04/01/PWB-grant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/2025/04/01/PWB-grant.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce that Dr. Guassi Moreira’s research proposal, “How Do Our Brains Regulate Emotions?”, was awarded a Secondary Data Analysis Grant by Plasticity of Well-Being (PWB) Network. The PWB Network is an NIH-funded research network comprised of scholars from the Center for Health Minds @ UW Madison, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, and Northwestern University. The goal of the network is to identify ways to measure people’s emotional health and well-being in everyday life. This award helps fund an ongoing project in the lab aimed at understand the inner workings of the developmental brain as it regulate emotions. The lab is grateful for the support of the PWB Network and the National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health.</p>]]></content><author><name>ben-scheve</name></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are pleased to announce that Dr. Guassi Moreira’s research proposal, “How Do Our Brains Regulate Emotions?”, was awarded a Secondary Data Analysis Grant by Plasticity of Well-Being (PWB) Network. The PWB Network is an NIH-funded research network comprised of scholars from the Center for Health Minds @ UW Madison, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, and Northwestern University. The goal of the network is to identify ways to measure people’s emotional health and well-being in everyday life. This award helps fund an ongoing project in the lab aimed at understand the inner workings of the developmental brain as it regulate emotions. The lab is grateful for the support of the PWB Network and the National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The CDN Lab receives an American Psychological Foundation Grant</title><link href="http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/2025/02/24/APF-grant.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The CDN Lab receives an American Psychological Foundation Grant" /><published>2025-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-23T20:57:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/2025/02/24/APF-grant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/2025/02/24/APF-grant.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce that Dr. Guassi Moreira’s research proposal, “Understanding the Impact of Emotion Regulation on Adolescent Risk-Taking and Substance Use”, was awarded The Trust Grant (in Honor of Eric A. Harris, EdD, JD) by the American Psychological Foundation. This award helps fund an ongoing study in lab aimed at understanding the interplay between emotion regulation and adolescent risk-taking in the context of substance use.</p>]]></content><author><name>ben-scheve</name></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are pleased to announce that Dr. Guassi Moreira’s research proposal, “Understanding the Impact of Emotion Regulation on Adolescent Risk-Taking and Substance Use”, was awarded The Trust Grant (in Honor of Eric A. Harris, EdD, JD) by the American Psychological Foundation. This award helps fund an ongoing study in lab aimed at understanding the interplay between emotion regulation and adolescent risk-taking in the context of substance use.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">News Coverage of Recent Lab Research</title><link href="http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/2024/10/15/news-coverage.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="News Coverage of Recent Lab Research" /><published>2024-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-23T20:57:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/2024/10/15/news-coverage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/2024/10/15/news-coverage.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to share that recent research from our lab was featured in Medical Xpress! The paper, “A behavioral signature to quantify how people attribute mental states to others,” was published in Communications Psychology. We developed a method to quantify the social value of a relationship based on a behavioral signature. Social value scores tracked with self-reported relationship quality and also predicted decision preferences on a range of tasks. For the medical xpress article <a href="https://medicalxpress.com/news/2024-10-behavioral-signature-quantify-people-attribute.html">click here</a>. For the original article <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s44271-024-00132-2">click here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>ben-scheve</name></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to share that recent research from our lab was featured in Medical Xpress! The paper, “A behavioral signature to quantify how people attribute mental states to others,” was published in Communications Psychology. We developed a method to quantify the social value of a relationship based on a behavioral signature. Social value scores tracked with self-reported relationship quality and also predicted decision preferences on a range of tasks. For the medical xpress article click here. For the original article click here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to the Computational Developmental Neuroscience Laboratory</title><link href="http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/2024/09/24/welcome-to-the-lab.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to the Computational Developmental Neuroscience Laboratory" /><published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-23T20:57:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/2024/09/24/welcome-to-the-lab</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cdnlab.psych.wisc.edu/CDNlab/2024/09/24/welcome-to-the-lab.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to announce the launch of the Computational Developmental Neuroscience Laboratory at the University of Wisconsin, Madison. Our lab is dedicated to understanding the neural mechanisms that shape socioemotional development during adolescence, with a particular focus on risky decision-making, emotion regulation, and social relationships. By combining cutting-edge neuroimaging techniques and computational modeling, we aim to shed light on how brain activity supports the complex behaviors that emerge during this pivotal stage of life.
Stay tuned for updates on our research projects, publications, and opportunities to get involved! You can also follow us on twitter @cdnlab_uwisc</p>]]></content><author><name>joao-moreira</name></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to announce the launch of the Computational Developmental Neuroscience Laboratory at the University of Wisconsin, Madison. Our lab is dedicated to understanding the neural mechanisms that shape socioemotional development during adolescence, with a particular focus on risky decision-making, emotion regulation, and social relationships. By combining cutting-edge neuroimaging techniques and computational modeling, we aim to shed light on how brain activity supports the complex behaviors that emerge during this pivotal stage of life. Stay tuned for updates on our research projects, publications, and opportunities to get involved! You can also follow us on twitter @cdnlab_uwisc]]></summary></entry></feed>